MARTIN JOSIPOVIC

Sr. React | NextJS | Node | NestJS | AWS

Contacts

Address:

Warsaw, Mazowieckie, Poland

Email:

martinjosipovic17@gmail.com

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/martinjosipovic-388613233/

Expertise

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python

Front-end Frameworks:

React, Vue, Electron, Flutter Web

Back-end Frameworks:

Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Net, Laravel, Django

Mobile App Frameworks:

React Native, Flutter

Cloud Services:

AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, Amazon DynamoDB, S3, AWS Cognito, EC2, Cloud Firestore, Firebase Realtime database, Firebase gateway

DevOps:

Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Docker, CI/CD, Webpack, Jest, Mocha, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, TDD, SOLID, DRY

Engineering & Technology:

Software Engineering, Reverse Engineering, Artificial Intelligence

About Me

I'm a full stack, polyglot developer who is constantly learning how to make web/hybrid apps faster, leaner,

and perfectly designed.

I have worked as a Software Engineer with more than 10 years of solid experience in IT, focusing principally

on full-stack development using Javascript, PHP, and Javascript frameworks. When I'm not behind a computer you will find me biking, hiking, skiing or planning my next backpacking trip around the globe.

Experience

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Self Employed Dec 2022 - Present

- Worked on 3 MVPs while working with young startups and individual clients
- Built a fully-integrated one-to-one live video co-shopping platform for customers and associates using React, Next.js, TypeScript, Twilio, and graphal
- Implemented work studio platform and OKR dashboard using React,
 TypeScript, AWS (lambda, API gateway, rest API, S3, Amplify), Node, MongoDB
- Built PWA for healthcare & fitness application using React, JavaScript, Ionic/React and several chrome extension apps in cross browsers.
- Developed an Ajax open-chatting, audio and video calling application, manipulated functionalities using Agora, WebRTC, Socket.io

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ANSYS ICA Gmbh

Jan 2020 - Dec 2022

- Developed a number of React SPAs and interactive features for a high-traffic media website.
- Utilized Node is to implement meta tag rewrites and server-side rendering.
- Implemented detailed pixel-perfect responsive designs with clean, modular Sass/CSS.
- Created the first mobile application within the whole company, using React Native, which was really well received by its customers.
- Created documentation for a use case to implement React Redux.
- Built Node.js and React app templates.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ANSYS ICA Gmbh Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

 Build an internal analysis and report generating user interface with JavaScript MVC structure via React and Redux.

MARTIN JOSIPOVIC

Sr. React | NextJS | Node | NestJS | AWS

- Designed and created the company website with React parallax effect via middleman framework and Skrollr library.
- Developed an analysis feature and provided various results visualized via React D3 and React HighCharts libraries.
- Designed and created a reusable React search module allowing users to compile a Solr search engine compatible query string.
- Developed a highly customizable report generating module with several high accessibility features including React drag and drop and React rich editor
- Developed real-time in-app notifications with websockets and React.
- Developed a readership module providing various visualization and comparison plots in React.
- Documented the internal design system and set up shared components with Storybook.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER Nortal Sep 2015 - Oct 2018

- Developed HTML prototypes and UI deliverables, such as wireframes, flowcharts, screen mock-ups, and interface design specifications.
- Responsible to manipulate HTML5, CSS3 in JQuery as well as making the pages dynamic using AJAX, JSON and XML.
- Developed/Design the application using XAMPP Windows, Apache, MySQL PHP 5.3 architecture and Yii Framework.
- Actively participated in all the phases of SDLC including Requirements Collection, Design & Analysis of the Customer Specifications, Development and Customization of the application.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER EG A/S Aug 2013 - Sep 2015

- Developed Coordinate Measurement Machine (CMM) integration and automation software for clients using a variety of programming languages and tools.
- Assisted in the assembly and development of robotic manufacturing cells, including a human machine interface.
- Instrumental in the creation of Intelligent Manufacturing & Inspection (IMI) software using PHP Laravel framework
- Wrote automated acceptance, unit, integration, and regression tests using PHPUnit and Selenium
- Successfully integrated 3D CAD model viewer/converter into IMI software using javascript and secure websockets
- Implemented client/server messaging system using Node.js and Redis.io

Education

Warsaw University of Technology Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science | 2009 - 2013